1991年，越南岘港
1991 DA NANG, VIETNAM
你好，这些都是你做的吗?
Hello, did you do all of this?
贝雷塔93通常很可靠。
Beretta 93 Usually dependable.
我们现在应该可以出发了。
We should be good to go now.
来吧。
Come on.
不要害怕。
Don't be afraid.
三十年后，罗马尼亚的布加勒斯特
THIRTY YEARS LATER THIRTY YEARS LATER BUCHAREST, ROMANIA
卧槽?你在开派对吗?
What the fuck? Are you having a party?
安东在哪里?
Where is Anton?
他为什么不接电话?
Why didn't he answer the phone?
瓦里!
Vali!
你父亲在找你。
Your father is looking for you.
起来!
Get up!
起来,瓦里!
Get up, Vali!
来吧，姑娘们，来吧。回家了。
Come on, girls, come on. Go home.
去,去!快点，离开这里。
Away, away! Come on, get out of here.
来吧，瓦利，我们走。
Come on Vali, let's go.
安东?
Anton?
瓦里他妈的在哪里?
Where the fuck is Vali?
你得看着他，瓦里他妈的在哪?
You had to look over him, where the fuck is Vali?
什么事?
Yes?
谁在说话?
Who's talking?
是我,瓦里。
It's me, Vali.
瓦里吗?
Vali?
告诉我你去哪了?你为什么不……有几个混蛋在酒店外面绑架了我。
Explain to me where did you go? Why don't you... Some assholes kidnapped me outside the hotel.
什么?谁?
What? Who?
谁绑架了你?
Who kidnapped you?
我他妈怎么知道?
How they fuck would I know?
他们现在想要300万欧元。
They want three million euros now.
瓦利，告诉他们我怎么样。
Vali, tell them how I am.
他们才不管你是谁，付钱就行!
They don't fucking care who you are, just pay!
他们想在两小时内拿到三百万欧元。
They want three million euros in two hours.
否则他们会像杀猪一样割了我的喉咙。
Or they'll cut my throat like a pig.
你怎么敢带走我儿子?
How dare you take my boy?
在这里。你想数一下吗?
There it is. You wanna count it?
你知道我是谁吗?
Do you know who I am?
唐Preda。
Don Preda.
布加勒斯特的屠夫，人类的杀手。
Butcher of Bucharest, Killer of Men.
告诉你的老板，一切都结束了。
Tell your boss it's done.
确切地说，你们是谁?
Exactly, who are you people?
我们只是…我们只是去找找不到的人。
We're just... We just find people who can't be found.
这笔钱。
The money.
你可能只能拿一个小时。
You gonna have it maybe for an hour.
然后我们把它抢回来，把你们俩切成块，喂我的猪。
Then we come take it back, cut you both into pieces and feed you to my pigs.
你不担心吗?
That doesn't worry you?
不。
No.
为什么?
Why?
我不是为钱来的。
I didn't come here for money.
我是来找你的。
I came here for you.
拦住她。她杀了Don Preda。杀了她。
Stop the girl. She killed Don Preda. Kill her.
你为什么这么拼命?
Why are you fighting so hard, huh?
你给我回家，混蛋。滚蛋!
You're going home, motherfucker. Fuck off!
我很好。
I'm good.
你们这些狗屎。你不能把我丢在这儿!
You fucking pieces of shit. You can't leave me here!
去你妈的，混蛋!
Fuck you, you bastards!
你拿了吗?
Did you take any, huh?
拿什么?
Take what?
钱。
Money.
都在那儿，对吧?
It was all there, right?
我们被雇来消灭目标。我们做到了。
We were paid to eliminate the target. We did that.
是啊，没人要的三百万黑钱…
Yeah, you know, three mil… dirty money… nobody's looking for…
只是说。
Just saying.
抱歉，我不知道你受伤了。
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't know you're hurting.
拜托。
Please.
这里是研发管道。你的漏洞已经修好了。
This is R & D Plumbing. Your leak has been fixed.
请将货款余额汇给我们……
Please remit the balance of your payment for the withd...
转账完成。
€7,000,000 Transfer complete Done.
你咳嗽得去看医生。
You need to see a doctor about that cough.
医生还是女巫?
Traditional or a witch?
你吗?肯定是女巫。
You? Definitely a witch.
我知道该给哪个女巫打电话。
I know just the voodoo queen to call.
伦敦
LONDON
切姆斯福德是一个血腥的战场。
Chelmsford was a bloody war zone.
每趟火车都晚点30分钟，像往常一样拥挤不堪。
Every train was 30 minutes late and jam-packed as always.
欢迎回来。
Welcome back.
谢谢你照顾她，你知道你是她唯一能忍受的人，对吧?
Thank you for taking care of her, you know you're the only one she'll tolerate, right?
你不在的时候她真的很刻薄。
She gets really mean when you're away.
大部分时间都和普鲁斯特在一起。
Spent most of the time hanging out with Proust.
这是真的吗?
Is that true?
才三个星期，你就只带回来这些?
Three weeks, and this is all you come back with?
啊，你知道卖家，他们知道你大老远跑来，所以他们就装出难到手的样子。
Ah, you know sellers, they know you've come all that way, and they play hard to get.
你不是就想那样杀人吗?
Didn't you wanna just kill people like that?
你以为你在干什么?
What do you think you're doing, huh?
有一天，他跟我说"70岁是新的30岁"
So, the other day, he says to me "70 is the new 30."
那只是老家伙说的话。
Well, that's just something old guys say.
他的协议做得怎么样了?他遵照医嘱了吗?
How is he doing with his protocol? Is he following the doctor's orders?
更像是听从自己的命令。
More like, following his own orders.
生日快乐。。。再也没有他妈的生日了。
Happy birth... No more fucking birthdays.
把生日塞进你的屁眼里。
Take birthdays and shove them up your ass.
混蛋。
Bastard.
多棒的玩具啊!
What a wonderful toy!
我看到你节省了蜡烛。
You skimped on the candles I see.
七十根有火灾隐患。
Seventy would have been a fire hazard.
你能给我们泡点茶吗?
Could you make us some tea please?
确定。
Sure.
好吧，许愿吧。
All right, make your wish.
生日快乐。
Happy birthday.
是的。
Yeah.
感谢你。
To thank you.
1958年的吉布森V型飞行车。
A 1958 Gibson Flying V.
这款产品仅生产了两年。
This was in production just two years.
全世界只有90个。
There is only 90 in the whole world.
我知道。
I know.
那个声音……
That sound…
它是木头。
It's the wood.
非洲榄仁树。
African limba.
其他的听起来都不像。
Nothing else sounds like it.
我都快放弃寻找的希望了。
I was just about giving up hope on finding one.
你到底是怎么……
How in the world did you…
你。
You.
你教我如何找到不想被发现的东西。
You taught me how to find things that didn't wanna be found.
阿尔伯特·金(Albert King)就是其中之一。
Albert King played one.
阿尔伯特·金(Albert King)曾演奏过这首曲子。
Albert King played that one.
不!
No!
你要哭了，是吧?
You're gonna cry now, aren't you?
那只是因为我不能按照它应该的方式来玩。
Only because I can't play it the way it needs to be played.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
双胞胎中的一个昨晚打电话给我，说她怀孕了。
One of the twins called me last night, said she was pregnant.
多佛的黛西吗?
Daisy in Dover?
不，是曼彻斯特的黛西。
No, Daisy in Manchester.
黛西在多佛是一条堤坝。
Daisy in Dover is a dyke.
拥有一个足够信任你的朋友是一件难得的礼物，在你请求之前，他不会试图帮助你。
It is a rare gift to have a friend who trusts you enough not to try and help until you ask.
如果你和那些人一起掉到池塘里，你会淹死的。
If you fell in the pond with those you'd drown.
好吧，如果我掉到池塘里没有它们，我可能会飘走。
Well, if I fell in a pond without them I would probably float away.
嗨,亲爱的。小心你的手指。
- Hi, honey. - Mind your fingers.
那是赫法咬的。
That hefa bites.
她还是个婴儿，什么都不懂。
She's a baby and doesn't know any better.
在那里。
There.
你有自己的秘密藏身之处。
You have your own secret hideout.
为什么我一点都不惊讶?
Why am I not surprised?
我买下了这栋楼。
I bought the building.
——什么?——书店。
- What? - The bookstore.
这是你的。自由和明确的。
It's yours. Free and clear.
你没必要这么做。
You didn't have to do that.
我知道，但这是你的激情所在。
I know, but it's your passion.
而且，我很高兴知道我不在的时候你还有工作要做。
And, it makes me feel good to know you'll have something to work on while I'm gone.
那是什么?
What is that?
那些是在另一边等着我的灵魂。
Those are the souls waiting for me on the other side.
我相信他们已经计划好了一个招待会。
I'm sure they have a reception planned.
啊，提前送走了这么多人。
Ah… sent away so many prematurely.
要么通过我的手，要么通过你。
Either by my hand or through you.
我们从来没有送走过没有来由的人。
We never sent anyone away who didn't have it coming.
也许吧。
Maybe.
但是，我敢肯定有不少鬼魂在那儿等着我挑骨头呢。
But… I'm sure there are quite a few spirits up there waiting for me with a bone to pick.
你真的相信你会上天吗?
You really believe you're going up?
你不?
Don't you?
卢卡斯海耶斯。
Lucas Hayes.
我需要我们的朋友帮我找到他。
I need our friend to find him for me.
我把他关押到1998年，巴黎，之后就没了。
I have him up till 1998, Paris, after that nothing.
——就发现了什么?——就找到。
- Just find? - Just find.
小心地，迅速地。
Discreetly, and with the quickness.
好吧。
Okay.
我可能得回越南了。
I may have to go back to Vietnam.
如果你和我一起去就好了。
It'd be nice if you went with me.
我再也不回去了。
I'm never going back there.
我们的过去再也回不去了，小变色龙。
Our past is never where we left it, little chameleon.
我们都有伤疤。
We all have scars.
你盯着它们看久了就会记得是怎么得到它们的。
You stare at them long enough you remember how you got them.
-嗨。——早上。
- Hi. - Morning.
蓝裙子上有个小裂口，我想和本尼谈谈这件事。
The blue dress has a small tear in it, I was hoping to talk to Benny about it.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
什么?
Of what?
我的胡子。
My, mustache.
抱歉，我没带隐形眼镜。
Oh, you know, I don't have my contacts in, sorry.
有趣。
Funny.
你等着，等女人变得像你这样…
You wait till this grows in women like you are gonna be so…
不,这是好的。我来帮你。
No, it's okay. I'll help you out.
我要你找到这个人。
I need you to find this guy.
什么?没有布加勒斯特外黑手党据点的卫星照片吗?
What? No satellite shots of a mafia compound outside Bucharest?
不，但那是你做得最好的。
No, but that was some of your better work.
穆迪想要这个人，卢卡斯·海耶斯，最后一次出现是98年在巴黎然后就没人了。
Moody wants this guy, Lucas Hayes, last seen in Paris in '98 and then nothing.
是的。
Yeah.
我马上就来。
I'll be with you in a second.
我能帮你吗?
Can I help you?
我在找一本书，一本旧书。罕见的。
Yeah, I'm looking for a book, an old book. Like, rare.
——“就像罕见”?-是的。
- "Like rare"? - Yeah.
要么是，要么不是。
Either they are or they aren't.
书不像木桩，你买不到五分熟的。
Books aren't like stake, you can't get them like medium rare.
——这很有趣。——讽刺。
- It's funny. - Sarcastic.
是的,但是有趣。
Yes, but funny.
听着，我老板的妻子在开派对她收集书籍，第一版的。
Listen, my boss' wife is having a party and she collects books, first editions.
-有什么特别的主题吗?——鸟。都是……
- Any particular subject? - Birds. It's Audobon's…
-《美洲鸟》?-对，就是这样。
- "Birds of America"? - Yeah, that's it.
他说她在找副本。
He said she's looking for a copy.
-第一版?-是的。
- A first edition? - Yeah.
——对不起。-你没有?
- Sorry. - You don't have it?
没有人知道，只有一个第一版，它在1991年以960万美元的价格卖给了一个私人买家。
No one does, only one first editions exists, it was sold to a private buyer in 1991 for a 9.6 million dollars.
哇,好吧。
Wow, okay.
看来我运气不太好。
Well, looks like I'm out of luck.
好吧。你觉得呢?也许诗歌?
All right. What do you think? Maybe poetry?
等一下…
Hang on…
这将会是派对的亮点。
It'll be the hit of the party.
塔穆雷和其他诗歌,这首我不知道。
TAMERLANE AND OTHER POEMS I don't... I don't know this one.
实际上是埃德加·爱伦·坡。
It's Edgar Allan Poe actually.
他的第一本诗集是匿名出版的。
His first collection of poems published anonymously.
你觉得她可能有吗?
You think she might have it?
表示怀疑。只印了50本。目前已知只有12个。
Doubtful. Only 50 copies were printed. Only 12 are known to exist.
多少钱?
How much?
我可以出二十六万五千美元卖给你。
I can give it to you for $265,000.
或许可以换成手镯?
Perhaps a bracelet instead?
她的手腕很精致，好主意。
She does have exquisite wrists, good idea.
还有别的吗?
Is there something else?
我觉得你很有趣。
I find you interesting.
-你是说…——你很有趣。
- You mean... - You're interesting.
漂亮，当然，不是那种装饰性的。
Beautiful, sure, not in that ornamental kind of way.
有趣的部分让我产生了疑问。
It's the interesting part that got me wondering.
想知道什么?
Wondering what?
我把我的号码给你之后多久你才会觉得我跟你一样有趣，然后给我打电话?
How long after I give you my number will it take you to decide that I'm just as interesting and give me a call?
27分钟。
Twenty seven minutes.
那么久?
That long?
首先我得假装取消约会，然后我得喂我的猫。
First I have to pretend to cancel my date and then I have to feed my cat.
只要6分钟。
That's six.
剩下的就是我欲擒故纵了。
The rest is me playing hard to get.
可爱。
Cute.
你带了多少个，先生…
How many of these are you carrying around, Mr…
伦布兰特。迈克尔·伦布兰特。
Rembrandt. Michael Rembrandt.
事实上，直到刚才我才有机会用。
Actually, I haven't had an occasion to use one until just now.
所以…
So…
有趣。
Interesting.
"曾经有一个喷泉，那里有许多美丽的花朵抬起头来"
"There rose a fountain once, and there full many a fair flower raised its head."
那是书上写的，对吧。
That was from the book, wasn't it.
"但养育他们的她早已死去，与这些蠢事毫无瓜葛"
"But she who rear'd them was long dead, And in such follies had no part."
这次你差点就抓到我了。
You almost got me on this one.
你没说我会跟踪一个八岁的孩子。
You didn't say I'd be tracking an eight year old.
卢卡斯·海斯确实在98年到达巴黎，但在99年3月回到了岘港。
Lucas Hayes did arrive in Paris in '98, but returned to Da Nang, March '99.
我知道的资料都在上面。
Everything else I have is on there.
B. B.金住在村门口
B. B. KING LIVE AT THE VILLAGE GATE
准备好了
READY TO GO
本尼?
Benny?
你得等我到，45分钟。
You'll stay up until I get there, 45 minutes.
卢卡斯·海斯，生于1990年4月5日。
Lucas Hayes, born April 5, 1990.
父亲:爱德华·海耶斯。妈妈:玛丽基督教。
Father: Edward Hayes. Mother: Mary Christian.
卢卡斯·海耶斯，1999年6月2日被送入圣基特里亚医院。
St. Quiteria Hospital Lucas Hayes, admitted to St Quiteria Hospital on June 2nd, 1999.
父亲:爱德华·海斯，1991年圣诞节遇刺身亡。没有其他的记录。
Father: Edward Hayes, assassinated at Christmas Day, 1991. No other records.
爱德华·阿瑟·海耶斯
Edward Arthur Hayes
被控战争罪的商人死于汽车炸弹袭击。
Businessman indicted for war crimes dies in car bomb attack.
爱德华·海耶斯昨天在岘港死于一场汽车爆炸
Edward Hayes… was killed in a car explosion in Da Nang yesterday.
Moody。
Moody.
“公司将继续，”誓言首席执行官爱德华·海耶斯说:“爱德华·海耶斯是我25年来的合作伙伴。”
"Company will continue," vows CEO "Edward Hayes was my partner for 25 years," said Vohl.
我将继续像他希望的那样管理我们的公司。”
I will continue to steer our company as he would have wanted me to."
Jossino Vohl
越南岘港
DA NANG, VIETNAM
狗屎!那他妈的是什么?
Shit! What the fuck is that?
他妈的。
Fuck.
亲爱的!来吧。
Honey! Come on.
没想到还能在这里见到你。
Never thought I'd see you here again.
也许你现在没看见我。
Well, maybe you're not seeing me now.
那婊子是谁?
Who's the bitch?
小比利…
Billy Boy…
我知道你和各种各样的人一起但现在你却和傻瓜一起?
I know you run with all kinds but now you're running with stupid?
去你妈的!
Fuck you!
嘿!去喝点东西，吃点糖，给大人们一点私人空间，好吗?
Hey! Go get a drink, sugar, and give the adults some privacy, huh?
啤酒!
Beers!
外面是你的车吗?
Is that your ride outside?
你的现在。
Yours now.
今天不是我的生日。
It ain't my birthday.
Jossino Vohl。
Jossino Vohl.
穆迪怎么样?
How's Moody?
他死了。
He's dead.
敬穆迪。
For Moody.
Vohl参与其中?
Vohl involved?
我不知道。但他知道是谁。
I don't know. But he knows who is.
-他很难杀-我只是想和他谈谈。
- He's gonna be hard to kill. - I just wanna talk to him.
Steverino !
Steverino!
是的,老板?
Yeah, Boss?
你在国家大厦做保安。
You work security at the State Tower.
我朋友要跟沃尔谈谈。
My friend there needs a few minutes with Vohl.
单独。
Alone.
那是不可能的。
Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
没有私人保安，他哪儿都不去。
He goes nowhere without private security.
他从不孤单。
The guy's never alone.
发生了什么?
What is happening?
我这么容易就能找到你，沃尔先生。
This is how easy it is for me to get to you, Mr. Vohl.
你明白吗?
Do you understand?
你是爱德华·海斯的朋友和生意伙伴，所以你对他短暂而有趣的一生了解最多。
You were friends and business partners with Edward Hayes, so you would know most about his short but interesting life.
很好，因为我有问题。
Good, cause I have questions.
你给我答案:如果我满意了，你就再也见不到我了，如果我不满意，我将是你最后见到的人。
You give me answers: if I'm satisfied you'll never see me again, if I'm not, I'll be the last thing you'll ever see.
我期待着你的消息。
I look forward to hearing from you.
晚上好,小姐。
Good evening, Miss.
很久没有这么年轻漂亮的女人给我她的电话号码了。
It's been a long time since such a beautiful young woman gave me her number.
你知道我是谁。
You know who I am.
乔西诺·沃尔，生于1945年4月。
Jossino Vohl, born in April, 1945.
法国人，全职居住在越南。
French national, residing full time in Vietnam.
一直和爱德华·海斯做生意直到他早逝。
Was in business with Edward Hayes until his untimely death.
现在你是顶级政治掮客还有些有趣的业余爱好。
Now you're a top political power broker with some interesting side hobbies.
看来你对我的简历很熟悉。
I see you're familiar with my resume.
我对你的商业活动不感兴趣，沃尔先生。
I am not interested in your business activities, Mr. Vohl.
我想谈谈你朋友的儿子，卢卡斯。
I want to talk about your friend's son, Lucas.
在我办公室，一小时后。
My office, one hour.
就我们俩?
We'll be alone?
我的律师会到场。
My lawyer will be present.
是站在你身后倒威士忌的人吗?
That would be the man standing behind you pouring a scotch?
很高兴见你,小姐。
Delighted, Miss.
非常准时。
Exactly on time.
请坐。
Please.
杜凯先生，我的私人律师。
Monsieur Duquet, my personal attorney.
要来点香槟吗?——爱德华·亚瑟·海耶斯
- Would you like some champagne? - Edward Arthur Hayes.
埃迪和我一起参与了一个铝土矿开采项目直到他出事。
Eddie and I were involved in a bauxite mining project together until his accident.
那不是意外，那是暗杀。
It wasn't an accident, it was an assassination.
我们是有用的。
We were useful.
这个国家具有可塑性，适合某些商业行为。
The country was malleable, ripe for certain business practices.
埃迪在玩弄一大堆精致的盘子。
Eddie was juggling a lot of delicate plates.
你怎么会对一个死了快三十年的人感兴趣?
What's your interest in a man who's been dead almost thirty years?
我对他儿子感兴趣。
I'm interested in his son.
卢卡斯海耶斯。
Lucas Hayes.
我很抱歉?
I'm sorry?
有三个人因为打听他的下落而死了。
Three people are dead because they inquired about him.
他杀了他们，我要去找他。
He had them killed and I'm going to find him.
我应该和他谈谈吗?
Should I be talking to him?
我和卢卡斯·海耶斯一点关系都没有。
I have no connection with Lucas Hayes.
这跟我有什么关系?
And what does any of this got to do with me?
我也在想这件事。
I was wondering the same thing.
沃尔先生过去的关系与任何人无关。
Mr. Vohl's past relationships are no one's concern.
当然也和你无关。
And certainly none of yours.
哦，我已经让他们与我有关了。
Oh, I've made them my concern.
太糟糕了。
Too bad.
我需要知道一切。
I need to know everything.
你是谁?
Who are you?
谁雇了你?
Who hired you?
为什么对卢卡斯·海耶斯感兴趣?
Why the interest in Lucas Hayes?
如果你愿意，我们可以换一种方式。
We can do this another way if you'd like.
他妈的放开我!
Fucking let me go!
去那里。
Get up there.
给我一把枪。
Hand me a gun.
喷水阀
SPRINKLER VALVE
你他妈以为你要去哪?
Where the fuck do you think you're going?
说出来。
Say it.
——去你妈的!——说它!
- Fuck you! - Say it!
她在那儿!
She's down there!
让我们从你的名字开始。
Let's start with your name.
为什么穆迪在找爱德华·海斯的儿子?
Why was Moody looking for Edward Hayes' son?
还有谁我们应该知道?
Who else out there should we know about?
他妈的!
Fuck!
有人能坚持这么久吗。
Anyone ever last this long.
反正现在也由不得我们了。
It's out of our hands now, anyway.
他吗?
Him?
那是漫长的27分钟。
That was a long 27 minutes.
我还在等你的电话。
I'm still waiting for your call.
没关系。
It's all right.
我不认为这些是针对我个人的。
I don't take these things personally.
骨头汤。
Bone broth.
有助于缓解炎症和瘀伤。
Helps with inflammation and bruising.
来。
Here.
小心。烫。小心。
Careful. It's hot. Watch it.
给。
There you go.
我自己就喜欢这个。
I like this myself.
给你，小口。
Here you go, small sips.
好吗?
Good?
我不想骗你，你不可能有好结果的。
Not gonna lie to you, there's not much of a chance this ends well for you.
外面那个家伙。
That guy out there.
我们为同一个人工作。
We work for the same individual.
老板有麻烦了。他打电话给他，让他处理。
Boss has a problem. He calls him, he takes care of it.
按我的口味，这有点强硬，但这不是我的决定。
Little heavy handed for my taste but that's not my call.
你朋友穆迪的事我很遗憾。
I'm sorry about your friend, Moody.
我没有参与其中。
I had no part in that.
或者书店的火灾。
Or the fire fight at the bookstore.
我是个事后诸葛明的人。
I'm an after-the-facts guy.
我来是为了确保没有后患。
I come in to make sure there's no loose ends.
我寻找那些看似无害，实则不然的东西。
I look for things that might seem benign, but aren't.
就像一个杀手开的书店，孩子，我从没想到会有这样的事发生。
Like a bookstore run by an assassin, boy, I never saw that one coming.
我完全误解你了。
I misread you completely.
我可以帮你离开这里。
I can help you out of here.
好吧?
Okay?
但你得帮我。
But you have to help me.
我是你最后的防线。
I'm your last line of defense.
路到尽头，没有更多的生命线。
End of the road, no more lifelines.
你明白吗?
You understand?
好吧。
All right.
你忘记把骨头漂白了。
You forgot to blanch the bones.
你的汤。
Your soup.
你在烤骨头之前必须先把它焯一下。
You have to blanch the bones before you roast them.
锁住矿物质，对治疗更有好处。
Locks the minerals in, it's better for healing.
你从她嘴里问出什么了吗?
You got anything out of her?
是的,没有。
Yes and no.
那他妈是什么意思?
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
意思是我明早会回来跟进她的情况。
Means I'll be back in the morning to follow up with her.
-我不需要你，伦勃朗。——嗯…
- I don't need you here, Rembrandt. - Well…
签支票的人却有不同的想法。
The man who signs the checks thought differently.
-哦,是吗?-是的。
- Oh, yeah? - Yeah.
为什么呢?
And why is that?
哦，我不知道。
Oh, I don't know.
也许是因为你没征得沃尔的同意就杀了他。
Maybe it's because you killed Vohl without asking his permission.
沃尔什么都知道，他跟我们有直接联系。
Vohl knew everything, he was a direct connection.
就会像帐篷一样折起来。
Would've folded like a tent.
你……是的，杀了我，你们都是一样的:先开枪再问问题。
You… yes, kill me, you're all the same: shoot first and ask questions later.
推迟那些强化审讯技巧。
And hold off on those enhanced interrogation techniques.
我希望她早上头脑清醒。
I want her clear-headed in the morning.
他明天就会把她击垮。
He'll break her tomorrow.
也许他已经把她击垮了。
Maybe he broke her already.
那老人非常想知道她知道些什么。
The old man is desperate to know what she knows.
我想知道如果他的"神奇小子"在发现之前杀了她会是什么感觉。
I wonder how it'd feel if his boy wonder ends up killing her before he finds out.
我猜他会去找一个新的神童。
I'm guessing he'll look for a new boy wonder.
就在我们开始了解对方的时候。
Just when we were getting to know each other.
我在机场，船厂和火车站都派了人。
I've got teams at the airport, shipyard and train station.
她不会跑的，她会舔自己的伤口。
She's not gonna run, she's gonna lick her wounds.
然后她就会来找你
Then she's coming after you.
好。
Good.
真的吗?
Really?
因为现在是4:0。她是取胜。
Cause right now it's 4:0. She's wining.
你在哪里买西装?
Where do you buy your suits?
因为我有个跟他一样高大的堂兄，他很不容易相处。
Cause I've got a cousin as big and tall and he's a hard time.
没有人的家。
Nobody's home.
我可以带你去边境。
Well, I can get you to the border.
伦敦现在对你来说可能不安全。
London may not be safe for you right now.
这是越南，安娜，你知道这里是什么样子的。
This is Vietnam, Anna, you know what's it like here.
你活着是欠穆迪的。
You owe it to Moody to stay alive.
我知道我欠他什么。
I know what I owe him.
走了。
Go.
你他妈以为我给你钱…
The fuck you think I gave you the money of...
到此为止，孩子。
End of the line, kid.
走!
Get in!
小心!
Watch out!
穆迪有他特有的美丽。
Moody was beautiful, in his way.
他是善良的。
He was kind.
不是通过努力，这就是他的一部分。
And not through effort, it was just a part of who he was.
他没有救我的命，他给了我一条命。
He didn't save my life, he gave me a life.
他知道我是谁，我变成了什么。
He knew who I was, what I've become.
他保护了我。
And he protected me.
海耶斯已经死了三十年了，沃尔死了更久。
Hayes has been dead for thirty years, Vohl was gone longer.
有一群坏人在找你。
You've got some very bad people looking for you.
卢卡斯·海耶斯杀了穆迪，他知道我在找他。
Lucas Hayes killed Moody, he knows I'm looking for him.
他最后的已知地点是圣奎特里亚医院。
His last known location is St. Quiteria Hospital.
最聋的莫过于不愿倾听的人。
Nobody is as deaf as those who don't wanna listen.
你好,阮女士。
Hello, Ms. Nguyen.
卫生部已经有一段时间没有来我们这儿了。
It's been some time since we've had a visit from the Ministry of Health.
要那么久远的记录…
And to request records from that far back…
是的,我知道。
Yes, I know.
我们希望能从中找到一些东西来帮助我们排除环境因素，因为我们正在进行一项研究。
We're hoping to find something in there that will help us rule out environmental factors, cause we are in the midst of a study.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
卢卡斯·海耶斯，早在我来这里之前。
Lucas Hayes, well before my time here.
2585024586.
收到，我让医生去查。
Copy, I'll get Doc on it.
好吧。
Okay.
医生来了，调出了他的记录。
Doc came through, pulled his records.
然后呢?
And?
坐下，卢卡斯·海斯于1999年6月2日被录取到圣基特里亚，根据他的记录，他从未离开过。
Sit down: Lucas Hayes was admitted to St. Quiteria on 2nd June, 1999, and according to his records never left.
抱歉，看来这孩子以克里斯蒂安的名字重新入院了。
I apologize, seems the boy was re-admitted under the name Christian.
克里斯蒂安，对，是他母亲的娘家姓。
Christian, right, his mother's maiden name.
我到的时候他已经在这里了，已经当了二十多年的病人了。
He was already here when I arrived, been a patient for more than twenty years.
他不喜欢别人碰他。
He doesn't like to be touched.
他不能说话。又聋又瞎。
He can't speak. Also deaf and blind.
他这样有多久了?
And how long has he been like this?
他六岁时被确诊，我相信，病情迅速恶化。
He was diagnosed when he was six, I believe, it regressed rapidly.
他能活这么久真是个奇迹。
It's a miracle he's lived as long.
谁来支付他的医疗费用?
And who pays for his care?
我们有一笔慷慨的捐赠。
We have a generous endowment.
这里的每个人都免费治疗。
Everyone here is treated for free.
哇!四个人死了，没有录像。
Wow! Four men dead, nothing on camera.
这地方看起来像个屠宰场。
Place looks like an abattoir.
是因为食物吗?
Was it the food?
你知道，虐待是不礼貌的。
You know, it was bad manners.
是啊，你不能这样对待一位女士。
Yeah, well, that's no way to treat a lady.
我不是淑女。
I'm no lady.
倒不是说我自己是个绅士。
Not that I was a gentleman myself.
我不会看轻你的。
I wouldn't sell yourself short.
来自你，这是一种赞美。
Coming from you, that's a compliment.
我正忙着呢…圣基特里亚的好姐妹们还好吗?
I'm in the middle of something... Hey, how were good sisters of the St. Quiteria?
好到让我知道我找错人了。
Good enough to let me know I've been looking for the wrong person.
好姑娘们。
Good gals out there.
圣基特里亚，你知道她是谁吗?
St. Quiteria, do you know who she was?
十五岁时，她领导了一场对抗罗马军团的游击战。
Fifteen years old, she led a guerrilla war against the Roman legions.
混蛋。
Bad ass.
他们砍下她的头，把剩下的喂狗。
They chopped off her head and fed the rest to the dogs.
同样,不礼貌。
Again, bad manners.
嘿，要一起吃晚饭吗?
Hey, you up for a dinner?
我可以回答几个问题，帮你省点时间。
I could answer some questions and save you some time.
我们说La Cinq怎么样?明天晚上，八点钟。
What do say if we say La Cinq? Tomorrow night, eight o'clock.
我是说你可以这么说。但我不会去的。
I mean you can say it. But I won't be there.
我会告诉你时间和地点。
I'll give you the time and place.
你对她很感兴趣。
You're intrigued by her.
好奇。
Curious.
我需要担心吗?
Need I worry?
晚宴名单，先生，200名宾客，都经过审核。
The gala list, sir, 200 guests, all vetted.
满屋子的富人和特权人士都在为崇高的事业捐赠大笔款项。
The joys of a room full of the wealthy and the privileged donating large sums for a noble cause.
快乐不会老。
Never gets old.
好。
Good.
你为什么要这么做?
Why did you do this?
处在我这个位置的人就该这么做，迈克尔。
It's what people in my position are supposed to do, Michael.
给予不幸的人。
Give to the less fortunate.
我问我是否应该担心。
I asked if I should be worried.
关于那个女人。
About the woman.
不。不用。
Nope. Not yet.
请在星期天之前把这件不愉快的事做完。
Please wrap up this unpleasantness by Sunday.
我不想在庆典前尴尬。
I don't wanna be embarrassed before the celebration.
哇。
Wow.
谢谢你,本。
Thank you, Ben.
这里的人都认识我。
They know me here.
干杯。
Cheers.
有人杀了我的一个朋友就因为他几年前完成的一份合同。
Someone killed a friend of mine because of a contract he completed years ago.
我问起这件事的人最后都死了。
And anyone I ask about it ends up dead.
这是为什么呢?
Why is that?
我不知道，但有些人可能会把它当成一种征兆。
I don't know, but some people might take it as a sign.
你为什么不把它当成一个未解之谜呢?
Why don't you just consider it a mystery best left unsolved?
但我喜欢推理小说。
But I like mysteries.
当我开始做这个的时候，我还是个怪人。
When I started this I was curios.
然后我从好奇变成了关心。
And then I went from curious to concerned.
现在呢?
And now?
我很暴躁。
I'm testy.
相信我，我暴躁的时候你是不会想认识我的。
An trust me, you don't wanna know me when I'm testy.
香港9毫米。
HK 9mm.
很好。
Very good.
从我的角度看不是。
Not from where I'm sitting.
谁在为那个孤儿买单?我想跟那个人谈谈。
Who's paying for the orphan kid? I'd like to talk to whoever that is.
那是不明智的。
That'd be unwise.
不智在杀一个曾是我父亲的人。
Unwise is killing a man who was a second father to me.
我们已经不明智了。
We are way past unwise.
这地方真不适合打人。
This is a really bad place for a hit.
高档餐厅，每个出口都有保安，更别提摄像头了。
High-end restaurant, the security at every exit, not to mention the cameras.
你知道吗，你已经知道了。
You know what, you already knew that.
我不是来杀你的…
Oh, I'm not here to kill you…
然而。只是为了得到答案。
Yet. Just to get answers.
你总是这样问吗?
You always ask like this?
是啊，我说话的时候喜欢引起别人的注意?
Yeah, I like to have peoples' attention when I talk, you know?
嗯…
Well…
你确实引起了下面那些男孩的注意。
you certainly have the attention of the boys down there.
听着，你至少射三颗子弹才能确保我死了。
Look, you're gonna have to put at least three in me to be sure.
四颗。
Four.
很好。给你留5颗。以防有什么麻烦。
Fine. That leaves you with five. In case there's trouble.
你觉得这就能让你离开这里吗?
You think that's enough to get you out of here?
四次快速射击，然后在混乱中慢慢走向出口。是的。
Four quick shots and then the slow walk to the exit amongst the chaos. Yeah.
可能会发生意想不到的事情。
Something unexpected could happen.
你知道，通常是这样的。
You know, it usually does.
SIG 226，后座力很猛。
SIG 226, it's got that great kick.
是的。
Yeah.
你觉得怎么样。我们第一次尴尬的沉默。
How about that. Our first awkward silence.
知道吗，我还不知道你叫什么。
You know what, I didn't get your name.
安娜。
Anna.
—荣幸。——我们将会看到。
- Pleasure. - We'll see.
我们还是忘了这些把戏吧。
What do you say we forget these tricks.
我们去找个好点的酒店吧。
Let's just go for a nice hotel.
你拿枪指着我的阴部然后叫我上床?
You point a gun at my pussy and then you ask me to bed?
我喜欢你的风格。
I like your style.
那个拿空心枪指着我蛋蛋的女人说。
Said the woman with hollow-points pointed at my balls.
希望这不会弄得一团糟。这是我最喜欢的鞋子。
Well, let's hope this doesn't get messy. These are my favorite shoes.
马诺洛，经典的四英寸高跟鞋。
Manolo's, classic four inch pumps.
一个了解坡和鞋类的人。
A man who knows Poe and footwear.
让我委婉地告诉你，你再这样下去，你会死的。
Let me put this to you delicately, you keep this up, you're gonna die.
越南一直是一个死亡之地。
Vietnam has always been a place of death.
只有幸运的人才能活着出来。我曾经很幸运。
Only lucky ones make it out alive. I was lucky once.
幸运不会有两次。
You don't get lucky twice.
我要找出杀害我朋友的凶手。
I'm going to find out who killed my friend.
然后呢?
And when you do?
我要结束他们的生命，还有任何阻碍我的人。
I'm going to end their life, and anyone standing in my way.
谢谢你让我度过了一个愉快的夜晚。
Thank you for a lovely evening.
我知道这听起来很疯狂，但我真的很想再见到你，换个环境。
Hey, I know it sounds crazy, but I'd really like to see you again under, you know, different circumstances.
这是私人时间。
This was personal time.
所以这是你见过的最好的环境。
So these are the best circumstances you'll ever see me in.
说话。
Speak.
搞定后给我打电话。
Call me when it's done.
我以为你去追查腐败的会计师了。
I thought you're off chasing corrupt accountants.
我找到了一个酒店房间里面有她的东西，包括她的护照。
I found a hotel room with all of her shit, including her passport.
名字叫娜迪娅可娃。
Name's Nadia Zhukova.
亚裔俄国人。
An Asian Russian.
男孩。
Boy.
你从来没有真正看到过。
You don't really see that ever.
干得好，你一定累坏了吧?
Good work, you must be exhausted, huh?
看来我晚了一天。
Looks like I'm a day late.
还差一美元。恐怕没吃多少。
And a dollar short. Didn't take much I'm afraid.
他唱得像只小鸟，不是吗?
He sang like a bird, didn't he?
我现在知道的所有事情。
All of the things I know now.
我知道你的上司是谁，就是批准杀害穆迪的人。
I know who your boss is, the man who sanctioned Moody's killing.
他是一条大鱼。
He's a big fish.
你勾引他的时候更有趣。
More fun when you hook him.
那我想…
Well, then I guess…
我想我们很快就能见面了。
I guess we'll be seeing each other real soon then.
比你想象的要快。
Sooner than you think.
你的手怎么了?
Hey, what happened to your hand?
下定决心:
Make up your mind:
杀我还是操我?
Kill me or fuck me?
真奇怪，我们在这家伙的床上，而他…
It's so weird that we're in this guy's bed while he's…
放上去。
up there.
你知道,上吊。
You know, hanging.
不。
No.
那就浪费了一张好床。
Would be a waste of a nice bed.
好吧。
Okay.
你干这行多久了?
How long have you been doing this?
不是，你知道，这个，但是…
Not, you know, this, but…
长到不会错过。
Long enough not to miss.
你很幸运。
You got lucky.
不。
Nah.
你不想让我死。
You don't want me dead.
然而。
Yet.
你为什么不杀了我?
Why haven't you killed me?
你能吗?
Could you?
我可以在你后脑勺上放两颗然后去做三明治。
I could put two in the back of your head and go make a sandwich.
好。
Well.
你总是说这不会成功的。
You always said this wasn't gonna work out.
不。
No.
这是我的经验，从来没有。
It's been my experience, it never does.
至少对另一个人来说不是。
At least not for the other guy.
有办法解决吗?
Have a way around that?
你掌握了所有的主动权。
You are holding all the cards.
我在看一个女人在大风中踩着绷紧的绳子从鲨鱼池上走过。
I'm watching a woman who walk over a shark tank on a tight rope in high winds.
你撑不过去的，安娜。
You're not gonna make it, Anna.
他是个坏人。
He's a bad man.
做了坏事的人。
Who's done very bad things.
你就这么躺着吗?
So, you just gonna lay there?
很高兴见到你，孩子。
Good to see you, kid.
进去。出去。
Get in. Get out.
你知道运气只有一次。
You know you only get lucky once.
是的。刚才有人告诉我的。
Yeah. Someone else just told me that.
好吧。
Okay.
上帝!
God!
-只是一点胶水。只是一点胶水。-你怎么回事!
- Just a little glue. Just a little glue. - What's wrong with you!
没事的，咬紧牙关。
It's okay, grit your teeth.
哦,上帝。
Oh, God.
我还是为克劳迪娅的事感到难过。
You know, I still feel really bad about Claudia.
她根本不会做饭，但她不应该那样死。
She couldn't cook worth a shit, but she didn't deserve to die like that.
我们开始吧。
Here we go.
好吧。
Okay.
好吧,好吧。我们在这里完成。
Okay, okay. We're done here.
你真以为他们能那么轻易地杀了我吗?
Did you really think they can kill me that easily?
在我把剩下的吹走之前，他本来就没有什么脸蛋儿。
Before I blew the rest of it off he didn't have much of a face to begin with.
我留下了足够的自我让当局认为是我干的。
And I left just enough of me for the authorities to think it was me.
很抱歉是你发现了他。
I'm sorry you had to be the one who found him.
无论如何，你都可以随机应变。
You could always think on your feet anyway.
今晚没那么多。
Not so much tonight.
这就是朋友该做的，对吧?
That's what friends are for, right?
哦,很好。我们是朋友了。
Oh, good. We're friends again.
你跟人上床了，不是吗?
You got laid, didn't you?
越来越依赖这些东西来缓解压力。
Depending more and more on this shit to take the edge off.
计划是什么?
So, what's the plan?
400英亩，要到那里你得徒步穿越12英里老鼠横行的丛林。
Four hundred acres, to get there you'd have to hike through 12 miles of rat-infested jungle.
只剩下河流，摄像头，声纳，巡逻艇。
That leaves the river, cameras, sonar, patrol boats.
还是个悲观的小混蛋，对吧?
Still a pessimistic little shit, aren't you?
你还是一只杀不死的蟑螂。
And you're still a cockroach you can't kill.
我是指好的方面。
I mean it in a good way.
他们知道你要来。
They know you're coming.
这是什么?
What is this?
这是避难室，在这里是避难掩体。
It's a panic room, in this case it's a panic bunker.
如果他进去了，你就完了。
If he gets in there, you're done.
所有的客人都是乘船来的，他们上岸后将接受检查。
All the guests arrive by boat, they'll be screened a moment they disembark.
周边封锁，现场安全。
Perimeter locked down and site secured.
我还从以色列增加了一个16人的小队来过夜。
And I've added an additional team of 16 out of Israel just for the night.
看来你什么都准备好了。
Seems like you got everything covered.
迈克尔。
Michael.
想法吗?
Thoughts?
威尼斯。
Venice.
每年的这个时候天气真的很好。
It's really nice this time of year.
你应该去。现在。
You should go. Now.
这些人根本不知道自己在跟谁打交道。
These guys have no idea who they're dealing with.
收到
Copy that.
你看起来有点紧张。
You look a little tense.
从加冕的王子到贩毒集团的头头，我保护过所有人。
I've protected everyone from crowned princes to cartel kingpins.
今晚不会有事的尤其是我们知道她长什么样之后。
Nothing's gonna happen tonight especially when we know what she looks like.
男孩……
Boy…
我真希望你提前拿到钱了。
I really hope you got paid upfront.
先生。
Sir.
什么吗?
Anything?
目前没有；至今没有一，二，三区安全。
Nothing so far. Sectors one, two and three are clear.
我在等第四区的报告。
I'm waiting on the reports from sector four.
谢谢你！
Thank you.
我怀着非常愉快的心情欢迎大家在这个非常昂贵的夜晚来到这里。
It is with great pleasure that I welcome you all here on this very expensive evening.
放眼望去，看到那么多熟悉的面孔、亲爱的朋友和亲密的生意伙伴，我那颗硬邦邦的心感到一阵暖意。
It warms my crusty heart to look across the room and see so many familiar faces, dear friends, and close business associates.
还有一些不熟悉的面孔，运气好的话，这些面孔不会持续太久。
As well as quite a few unfamiliar faces that with luck will not remain so for long.
也许我甚至发现了一些我以前的敌人。
Perhaps I may even have spotted a few former foes of mine.
我要特别感谢你们的到来，感谢你们认识到自己的错误。
I want especially to thank you for coming, and for seeing the error of your ways.
这么多年来，我很满意地认识到，没有什么比做好事更好的净化心灵的方式了，为他人做出无私的行为和善良的行为，
Over these considerable years, I've learnt to my great satisfaction there is no better way to cleanse the soul than to do good to perform selfless deeds and acts of kindness to sacrifice for others,
最重要的是慷慨地给予。
and most importantly to give generously.
正是由于你们的慷慨精神，我们才能够丰富和改善如此多的婴儿、儿童和急需照顾的青年男女的生活
It is due to your generous spirit that we've been able to enrich and enhance the lives of so many infants, children, young men and women in desperate need of care
如果没有你们每一个人，这是不可能实现的。
to a degree that would have been impossible to achieve without every one of you.
女士们先生们，感谢你们今晚的盛情款待。
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you for the privilege of being your host tonight.
感谢你允许我把手伸进你的口袋和钱包里，但这是有意义的。
And for allowing me to slide my hands into your pockets and purses, but for a worthy a cause.
圣奎特里亚修女的工作很出色…所以…
The sisters of St. Quiteria do outstanding work… So…
用心去付出。
…Give with your heart.
对于一个已经死了三十年的人来说，你看起来真不错，海耶斯先生。
You look really good for a man who's been dead thirty years, Mr. Hayes.
你怎么进来的?
How'd you get in here?
技术。总有一天会毁了我们所有人。
Technology. It just gonna fuck us all one day.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是一只大坏狼，当地球上有人认为你的时间到了，我就会来抓你。
I'm the big bad wolf that comes to get you when someone on this Earth decides your time is up.
Moody。
Moody.
复活是个贱人，不是吗?
Resurrection is a bitch, ain't it?
你是来完成这项工作的，是吗?
You've come to finish the job, haven't you?
那么多年前你雇我来杀你，对吧?
Well, you did hire me all those years ago to kill you, right?
到底谁在那辆车里?
Who was really in that car?
这有关系吗?可支配的资产。没有任何重要人物。
Does it matter? Disposable asset. No one of any consequence.
你看，我就指望像你这样的人说这种屁话。
You see, that's the kind of shit I expect someone like you to say.
“没有什么重要人物。”
"No one of any consequence."
“像我这样的人”?
"Someone like me"?
伙计，我在道德上不可能完全正确。
Man, I can't be all morally right.
我以杀人为生，坏人，提醒你，但是。
I kill people for a living, bad people, mind you, but still.
我从不假装自己是别的什么人。
I never pretend to be anything else.
你，你是众多知名慈善事业的核心人物。
You, you're front and center of a dozen high-profile charitable causes.
全世界都把你看得清清楚楚。
The world sees you as clean as first fucking snow.
但你手上都是屎。
But your hands are covered in shit.
血，从沙林毒气到人口贩卖的一切。
Blood, everything from sarin gas to human trafficking.
所以你知道我为什么要安排自己的死亡。
So you know why I had to arrange my demise.
我有了一个儿子，在很多方面都出乎意料。
I had a son, unexpected in many ways.
但我无法理解的是我对这个孩子的爱有多深，这个不完美的，完美的，脆弱的男孩。
But what I couldn't fathom was the depths of love I had for this child, this imperfect, wonderful, vulnerable boy.
如果我死了，卢卡斯就不会受到任何威胁或伤害。
If I were dead, Lucas would be free from any threats or harm.
废话。
Bullshit.
你也许爱你的儿子，海耶斯先生，但那是你消失的机会。
You may love your son, Mr. Hayes, but that was your chance to disappear.
你很精明的。
You're very astute.
没人会去找死人。
No one looks for a dead man.
我能够在体面的外衣下继续下去，这让我能够……变成一个更大的怪物。
I was able to continue behind the shroud of respectability that allowed me to... To become a bigger monster.
讽刺的是，海耶斯先生，我只是想向你儿子赔罪因为我把他的父亲从他身边带走了。
The irony of all of this, Mr. Hayes, is that I was just trying to make amends to your son for taking his father away from him.
这一切都是你自找的。
You brought all of this on yourself.
安娜。
Anna.
你看起来不太好。
You don't look so good.
我不知道。
I don't know.
一杯苹果马提尼和一升AB阳性血就没事了，对吧?
Nothing an Apple Martini and a liter of AB positive won't fix, huh?
你觉得我有多大机会得到这些?
Hey, what do you think the chances are of me getting either?
晕倒。
Faint.
一些有趣的东西吗?
Something funny?
我觉得很有趣，你觉得自己比我强。
I find it amusing you think you're better than me.
而不是更好。
Not better.
不同。
Different.
大多数人都是好人，海耶斯先生。
You see, most people are good, Mr. Hayes.
偶尔他们会做一些明知是坏事的事。
Then occasionally they do something they know is bad.
有些人很坏，他们每天都在努力控制自己。
Some people are bad, and they struggle every day to keep it under control.
有些人腐败到极点，一点也不在乎，那就是我。
Others… corrupt to the core and just don't give a damn, that would be me.
但是邪恶……
But evil…
邪恶是完全不同的生物，海斯先生。
Evil is a completely different creature, Mr. Hayes.
邪恶认为邪恶是好的，它的行为是正当的。
Evil believes bad is okay, its actions are justified.
脱离良心的暴力，不管付出什么代价，也不管对谁造成什么伤害。
Violence divorced from conscience, no matter what toll it takes or who it takes it upon.
朋友，这就是我们分道扬镳的地方。
And there, my friend, is where we part ways.
我只是个想为自己的罪行付出代价的坏人。
I'm just a bad man who's looking to pay for his sins.
我明白了。
I see.
所以你是来问心无愧的吗?
So you are here to clear your conscience first?
你不可能活着离开这里。
You'll never get out of here alive.
我从没想过。
I never intended to.
还有一件事。
One more thing.
你差点杀了那个老人。
You could have killed the old man.
你为什么不?
Why didn't you?
计划不是这样的。
That wasn't the plan.
安娜:太棒了。位置
ANNA: IT'S BEEN A BLAST. LOCATION
别管我!
Leave me alone!
不!不!
No! No!
不!妈妈!
No! Mom!
妈妈!
Mom!
你怎么了?
What took you?
只是出去吃点东西。
Just out for a bite.
你就站在那儿?
You just gonna stand there?
现在。
For now.
没必要这样，安娜。
It doesn't have to be this way, Anna.
不了。
Not anymore.
我们最终都要为自己的罪孽付出代价。
We all have to pay for our sins eventually.
不必非得是今天。
Doesn't have to be today.
我累了。
I'm tired.
我想要和平。
I want peace.
你不在的时候，我不能把它拿走。
And I can't have it while you're out there.
如果我说你可以呢?
What if I told you you could?
是吗?
Yeah?
脑袋后面挨两枪，然后去吃个三明治。
Two in the back of the head, and then go have a sandwich.
你无法买回你的过去，安娜，你无法改变你的出身，但你可以改变你的未来。
You can't buy back your past, Anna, can't change where you came from, but you can change where you're going.
那会在哪？
Where would that be?